Let me also briefly show this
example from the slides in action.
So, this was the physics animation/simulation
example. So, throwing a ball.
And what I wanted to explain or briefly
discuss here was the scope issue.
So, the point that here the x and y can use
the t without an explicit somehow function
argument.
Why is that?
Because what I said… because they are
in the local definition here, right?
And this scope from the t extends
also through local definitions.
So, what would we have had to do if we somehow
wanted to have this as a top-level definition?
So, it wouldn't directly work and
would be surprising if it worked.
Why should it?
So, if we simply had these on the
top level, then this wouldn’t work.
And you see it already here. Why is that?
We get all these arrows, where somehow, Haskell
is not happy that there is this variable
not in scope.
Yes.
Okay.
And then how could I bring it in scope?
Well, since I have moved this now out of
this local scope, the t is not known here.
So, this t here is local for this function.
So, the other function doesn’t know it.
So, I could actually introduce it, right?
I could say, well, let me make these x and y
into functions, which take t as an argument,
then this works.
But of course, these are now not
the x and y that are used here.
So, they are still using the x and y from here,
because again, now these x and y are in scope
for this whole function.
But this x and y, they are simply names
of some other functions on the top level.
Let me actually get rid of these local definitions
so that I'm sure that this x and this y actually
refer to these x and y.
But now, of course, there's another error.
And if you look at it basically,
it boils down to a type issue.
So, now x and y are used here as numbers,
but I have just turned them into functions.
So, what I could do is to actually
pass the t along to these functions.
Okay, then everything would compile, apparently.
At least there are no obvious
errors that are shown here.
And actually, if I compile and
run it, it will work, I hope.
Yes, it does work and it does the same as
before, but of course, it's not as nicely
expressed, right?
So, this local definition use and actually
the scoping of local variables or variables
introduced in the scope of function definition…
this also extending to the local definitions
here,
as we had before, is of
course a nice thing to have.
Simply, we can have these expressions
here.
And they are referring to this t, etc.
So, actually translating this back
into the function that you saw before.
I don't have to do this now, you can download
the original version from the Moodle course.